Painting Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- Painting Germany (Box 106)
  - Artists Known (Box 108)
    - MULTSCHER, Hans, 1400-1467 (Box 118)
    - MUNTER, Gabriele, 1877-1962 (Box 118)
    - NAUEN, Heinrich, 1880- (Box 118)
    - NOLDE, Emil, 1867-1956 (Box 118)
    - NOTKE, Bernt, ca. 1440-1509 (Box 118)
    - OESTERLEY, Carl Wilhelm, 1805-1891 (Box 118)
    - OLDACH, Julius, 1804-1830 (Box 118)
    - OVERBECK, Johann Friedrich, 1789-1869 (Box 118–119)
    - PACHER, Michael, d. 1498 (Box 119)
    - PADUA, P.M., 20th century (Box 119)
    - PECHSTEIN, Max, 1881-1955 (Box 119)
    - PFOOR, Franz, 1782-1812 (Box 119)
    - PILOTY, Karl von, 1826-1886 (Box 119)
    - POLLACK, Jan (Box 119)
    - REINHART, Johann Christian (Box 119)
    - RICHTER, Hans, 1888-1975 (Box 119)
    - RICHTER, Ludwig, 1803-1884 (Box 119)
    - RING, Hermann Tom, 1521-ca. 1599 (Box 119)
    - ROHLTS, Christian, 1849- (Box 119)
    - RUGENDAS, Johann Moritz, 1802-1858 (Box 119)
    - RUNGE, Philipp Otto, 1777-1810 (Box 119)
    - SANDRART, Jakob von, 1630-1708 (Box 119)
    - SCHAFFNER, Martin, fl. 1508-1536 (Box 119)
    - SCHEL, Sebastian (Box 119)
    - SCHEICH, Edward, 1812-1874 (Box 119)
    - SCHICK, Gottlieb, 1779-1812 (Box 120)
    - SCHINKEL, Karl Friedrich, 1781-1841 (Box 120)
    - SCHLEMMER, Oskar, 1888-1943 (Box 120)
    - SCHMIDT, Martin Johann, 1718-1801 (Box 120)
    - SCHMIDT-ROTTLUFF, Karl, 1884-1976 (Box 120)
    - SCHNORR von Carolsfeld, Julius, 1794-1872 (Box 120)
    - SCHONGAUER, Martin, ca. 1430-1491 (Box 120)
    - SCHWARTZ, J.C. (Box 120)
    - SCHWEICKHARDT, Heinrich W. (Box 120)
    - SCHWITTERS, Kurt, 1887-1948 (Box 120)
    - SEITZ, Ludwig, 1844-1908 (Box 120)
    - SOEST, Conrad van, fl. 1405-1422 (Box 120)
    - SOEST, Gerard von, 1637-1681 (Box 120)
    - SOREAU, Jan, fl. 1615-1638 (Box 120)
    - SPIEGLER, Franz (Box 120)
    - SPITZWEG, Karl, 1808-1885 (Box 120)
    - STEFFECK, Karl, 1818-1890 (Box 120)
    - STOSS, Veit, ca. 1445-1542 (Box 120)
    - STRIGEL, Bernhard, 1460-1528 (Box 120)
    - STUCK, Franz von, 1863-1928 (Box 120)
    - THOMA, Hans, 1839-1924 (Box 120)
    - TISCHBEIN, Johann Heinrich Wilhelm, 1751-1829 (Box 120)
    - UHDE, Fritz von, 1848-1911 (Box 120)
    - VISCHER, Peter the Younger,, 1487-1528 (Box 120)
    - WASMANN, Friedrich, 1805-1886 (Box 120)
    - WINTERHALTER, Franz Xavier, 1805-1875 (Box 120)
    - WITZ, Konrad, ca. 1400-ca. 1445 (Box 120–121)
    - WOHLGEMUT, Michael (Box 121)
    - WOLS, 1913-1951 (Box 121)
- Painting Holland (Box 121)
  - Master of Alkmaar (Box 121)
  - Master of Delft (Box 121)
  - Master of Manna (Box 121)
  - Master of the Virgo Intervirgines, fl. ca. 1480-1500 (Box 121)
  - Artists (Box 121)
    - AELST, Willem van, 1627-after 1687 (Box 121)
    - ANDRIESSEN, Hendrick, 1607-1656 (Box 121)
    - ANTHONISZ, Cornelis, ca. 1505-after 1553 (Box 121)
    - APPEL, Karel, 1921-2006 (Box 121)
    - AST, B. van de (Box 121)
    - AVERCAMP, Berend (Box 121)
    - AVERCAMP, Hendrick, 1585-1634 (Box 121)
    - BABUREN, Dirck van, ca. 1595-1624 (Box 121)
    - BACKER, Jacob Adriaenz, 1608-1651 (Box 121)
    - BASSEN, Bartholomeus, 1590-1652 (Box 121)
    - BERCHEM, Nicolaes, the elder, 1620-1683 (Box 121)
    - BERCKHEYDE, Gerrit, 1638-1699 (Box 121)
    - BERCKHEYDE, Job (Box 121)
    - BEVERLOO, Cornelius van (Box 121)
    - BEYEREN, Abraham van (Box 121)
    - BULERT, Jan van (Box 121)
    - BLOCKLANDT, Antoine van, 1532-1583 (Box 121)
    - BLOEMART, Abraham, 1584-1651 (Box 121)
    - BOL, Ferdinand, 1616-1680 (Box 121–122)
    - BOR, Paulus (Box 121–122)
    - BOSCHAERT, Abraham, 1612-1643 (Box 121–122)
    - BOTH, Andries Dirksz, 1608-1649 (Box 121–122)
    - BOTH, Jan, ca. 1618-1652 (Box 121–122)
    - BOUTS, Dirk (see FLANDERS) (Box 121–122)
    - BRAY, Jan de, ca. 1627-1692 (Box 122)
    - BREENBERGH, Bartholomeus, 1599-1659 (Box 122)
    - BRIZE, Cornelis, ca. 1630-ca. 1670 (Box 122)
    - BURGH, Hendrick van der (Box 122)
    - BUYTENWECH, Willem, 1585-1627 (Box 122)
    - CAPPELLE, Jan van der, 1624-1679 (Box 122)
    - CITROEN, Paul, 1896-1983 (Box 122)
    - CLAESZ, Pieter, ca. 1597-1660 (Box 122)
    - CLEVE, Hendrick van, 1525-1589 (Box 122)
    - CODDE, Pieter Jacobsz, 1599-1678 (Box 122)
    - COLONIA, Adam de, 1634-1685 (Box 122)
    - COLYER, Edwaert, d. 1702 (Box 122)
    - COORTE, Adriaen, fl. 1685-1723 (Box 122)
    - CORNEILLE, 1922- (Box 122)
    - CORNELISZ. Van Haarlem, Cornelis, 1562-1638 (Box 122)
    - CUYP, Albert, 1620-1691 (Box 122)
    - DANCKERTS, Henry, ca. 1630-ca. 1680 (Box 122)
    - DEELEN, Dirk van (Box 122)
    - DE JONGHE (Box 122)
    - DIJCK, Floris Claesz van, 1575-1651 (Box 122)
    - DOESBURG, Theo van, 1883-1931 (Box 122)
    - DONGEN, Kees van, 1877- (Box 122)
    - DOU, Gerrit, 1613-1675 (Box 122–123)
    - DROST, Willem (Box 123)
    - DUJARDIN, Karel, 1622-1678 (Box 123)
    - DUYSTER, Willem, 1598-1635 (Box 123)
    - ECKHOUT, Albert (Box 123)
    - EECKHOUT, Gerbrandt van der, 1621-1674 (Box 123)
    - ELIASZ, Nicholaes, d. ca. 1535 (Box 123)
    - ENGELBRECHTS, Cornelis, 1468-1533 (Box 123)
    - EVERDINGEN, Allart van, 1621-1675 (Box 123)
    - EWORTH, Hans, ca. 1625-after 1578 (Box 123)
    - FABROTIUS, Bernard, fl. 1650-1672 (Box 123)
    - FABROTIUS, Carel, 1614-1654 (Box 123)
    - GEERTGEN, tot Sint Jan, ca. 1460-ca. 1490 (Box 123)
      - Berlin (Box 123)
      - London (Box 123)
      - Vienna (Box 123)
    - GELDER, Aert de, 1645-1727 (Box 123)
    - GHEYN, Jacob de, II, ca. 1565-1629 (Box 123–124)
    - GOLTZIUS, Hendrik, 1558-1617 (Box 124)
    - GOYEN, Jan van, 1596-1656 (Box 124)
    - HALS, Dirk, 1591-1656 (Box 124)
    - HALS, Frans, 1584-1666 (Box 124)
      - Amsterdam (Box 124)
      - Berlin (Box 124)
      - Cassel (Box 124)
      - Haarlem (Box 124)
        - Governors of Old Men's Home (Box 124)
        - Lady Governors of Old Men's Home (Box 124)
        - Officers of S. Adrian, 1627 (Box 125)
        - Officers of S. Adrian, 1633 (Box 125)
        - Officers of S. George, 1616 (Box 125)
        - Officers of S. George, 1627 (Box 125)
        - Officers of S. George, 1639 (Box 125)
      - London (Box 125)
        - National Gallery (Box 125)
        - Wallace Collection (Box 125)
      - New Haven (Box 125)
      - New York (Box 125)
      - Paris (Box 125)
      - Washington (Box 125)
    - HEDA, Gerrit Willenmsz, ca. 1620-ca. 1702 (Box 125)
    - HEDA, Willem C., 1594-1680 (Box 125)
    - HEEM, Cornelis de, 1631- (Box 125)
    - HEEM, Jan Davidsz de, 1606-ca. 1683 (Box 125)
    - HEEMSKERCK, Egbert van, 1634-1704 (Box 125)
    - HEEMSKERCK, Maerten van, 1498-1574 (Box 125)
    - HELST, Bartholomeus van der, 1613-1670 (Box 125)
    - HEY, Jean (Box 125)
    - HEYDEN, Jan van der, 1637-1712 (Box 126)
    - HOBBEMA, Meindert, 1638-1709 (Box 126)
      - Amsterdam (Box 126)
      - London (Box 126)
      - New York (Box 126)
      - Washington (Box 126)
    - HONTHORST, Gerard van, 1590-1656 (Box 126)
    - HOOCH, Peter de, 1629-1684 (Box 126)
      - Amsterdam (Box 126)
      - Berlin (Box 126)
      - London (Box 126)
        - National Gallery (Box 126)
        - Wallace Collection (Box 126)
      - New York (Box 126)
      - Washington (Box 126)
    - HOOGSTRATEN, Samuel van, 1627-1678 (Box 126)
    - HUYSUM, Jan van, 1682-1749 (Box 126–127)
    - ISRAELS, Joseph (Box 127)
    - JANSSENS, Pieter (Box 127)
    - JANSZ, Jan (Box 127)
    - JONGKIND, Johan Barthold, 1819-1891 (Box 127)
    - KALF, Willem, 1619-1693 (Box 127)
    - KETEL, Cornelis, 1548-1616 (Box 127)
    - KEYSER, Thomas de (Box 127)
    - KONINCK, Philips de, 1619-1689 (Box 127)
    - KONINCK, Salomon, 1609-1656 (Box 127)
    - LAER, Pieter Jacobsz van, 1592-1642 (Box 127)
    - LAIRESSE, Gerard de, 1640-1771 (Box 127)
    - LASTMAN, Pieter, 1583-1633 (Box 127)
    - LECK, van der (Box 127)
    - LEEMPUT, Remee van, 1607-1675 (Box 127)
    - LEEMPUT, Remee van, 1607-1675 (Box 127)
    - LIEVENSZ, Jan, 1607-1674 (Box 127)
    - LOO, Jacob van, 1614-1670 (Box 127)
    - LUCAS van Leyden, ca. 1494-1533 (Box 127)
    - MAES, Nicolas, 1634-1693 (Box 127)
      - Amsterdam (Box 127)
      - London (Box 127–128)
    - MARIS, Matthijts, 1839-1917 (Box 128)
    - MARIS, Willen, 1844-1910 (Box 128)
    - MARSENS van Schrieck, Otto, 1619-1678 (Box 128)
    - MATHAM, Jacob, 1571-1631 (Box 128)
    - MAUVE, Anton, 1838-1888 (Box 128)
    - MEEGEREN, Han van, 1889-1947 (Box 128)
    - METSU, Gabriel, 1629-1667 (Box 128)
      - New York (Box 128)
    - MIEREVELT, Michiel van, 1567-1641 (Box 128)
    - MIERIS, Frans van, 1635-1681 (Box 128)
    - MOEYAERT, Claesz, 1529-1655 (Box 128)
    - MOLENAER, Jan Miense, ca. 1610-1668 (Box 128)
    - MOLIJN, Pieter de, 1595-1661 (Box 128)
    - MOMPER, Frans de (Box 128)
    - MONDRIAN, Piet, 1872-1944 (Box 128)
      - Amsterdam (Box 128)
      - Basel (Box 128)
      - Blarkum (Box 129)
      - Hague (Box 129)
      - New Haven (Box 129)
      - New York (Box 129)
      - Otterlo (Box 129)
    - MOREELSE, Paul (Box 129)
    - MOSTAERT, Jan, ca. 1475-ca. 1556 (Box 129)
    - MULLER, Jan, 1571-1628 (Box 129)
    - MYTENS, Daniel the Elder (Box 129)
    - NEER, Aert van der, 1603-1677 (Box 129)
    - NEER, Eglon H. van der, ca. 1634-1703 (Box 129)
    - OSTADE, Adriaen van, 1610-1685 (Box 129)
    - OSTADE, Isack van, 1621-1649 (Box 129)
    - OUWATER, Aelbert van, fl. 1430-1460 (Box 129)
    - PEETERS, Clara, ca. 1594-1657 (Box 129)
    - PIETERSZ, Aert, 1550-1612 (Box 129)
    - POELENBURG, C. van, 1586-1667 (Box 129)
    - POST, Franz, 1612-1680 (Box 129)
    - POTTER, Paulus, 1625-1654 (Box 129)
    - PYNACKER, Adam, ca. 1620-1673 (Box 130)
    - PYNAS, Jan (Box 130)
    - RAVESTYN, Jan (Box 130)
    - REMBRANDT van Rijn, 1606-1669 (Box 130)
      - Drawings (Box 130)
        - Amsterdam (Box 130)
        - Bayonne (Box 130)
        - Berlin (Box 130)
        - Bremen (Box 130)
        - Cambridge (Box 130)
        - Dresden (Box 130)
        - Haarlem (Box 130)
        - London (Box 131)
        - Munich (Box 131)
        - New York (Box 131)
          - Private Collection (Box 131)
        - Oxford (Box 131)
        - Paris (Box 131)
          - Louvre (Box 131)
          - Petit Palais (Box 131)
          - Collection of F. Lugt (Inst. Neerlandeis) (Box 131)
        - Rotterdam (Box 131)
        - Stockholm (Box 131)
        - Vienna (Box 131)
        - Washington (Box 132)
        - Weimar (Box 132)
      - Paintings (Box 132)
        - Amsterdam (Box 132)
          - Anatomy Lesson of Dr. J. Deyman (Box 132)
          - Holy Family at Night (Box 132)
          - Jeremiah Lamenting the Destruction of Jerusalem (Box 132)
          - Jewish Bridal Couple (Box 132)
          - Joseph Telling the Dream (Box 132)
          - Night Watch (Box 132)
          - Peter Denying Christ (Box 132)
          - Stone Bridge (Box 132)
          - Syndics of Cloth Guild (Box 132–133)
          - Portraits (Box 133)
            - Portrait of Maria Trip (Box 133)
            - Rembrandt's Mother (Box 133)
            - Self-Portrait (Box 133)
        - Basel (Box 133)
        - Berlin (Box 133)
          - Man with Golden Helmet (Box 133)
          - S. John the Baptist Preaching (Box 133)
          - Susanna and the Elders (Box 133)
        - Boston (Box 133)
        - Braunschweig (Box 133)
        - Brussels (Box 133)
        - Cassel (Box 133–134)
        - Chatsworth (Box 134)
        - Chicago (Box 134)
        - Cologne (Box 134)
        - Copenhagen (Box 134)
        - Detroit (Box 134)
        - Dresden (Box 134)
        - Florence (Box 134)
        - Frankfurt (Box 134)
        - Glasgow (Box 134)
        - Hague (Box 134)
          - Anatomy Lesson (Box 134)
          - Portraits (Box 134)
          - Saul and David (Box 134)
        - Hamburg (Box 134)
        - Leningrad (Box 134–135)
        - London (Box 135)
          - National Gallery (Box 135)
            - Christ Presented to the People (Box 135)
            - Adoration of the Shepherds (Box 135)
            - Elderly Man as S. Paul (Box 135)
            - Old Man in an Arm Chair (Box 135)
            - Scholar in his Study (Box 135)
            - Woman Taken in Adultery (Box 135)
            - Woman Bathing (Box 135)
            - Portraits (Box 135)
              - Portrait of Old Woman (Box 135)
              - Portrait of Philps Lucasz (Box 135)
              - Portrait of Marg. de Geer (Box 135)
              - Saskia in Arcadian Costume (Box 135)
            - Self-Portraits (Box 135)
              - Self-Portrait, age 34 (Box 135)
              - Self-Portrait at an advanced age (Box 136)
        - Los Angeles (Box 136)
        - Madrid (Box 136)
        - Manhasset (Box 136)
        - Melbourne (Box 136)
        - Minneapolis (Box 136)
        - Moscow (Box 136)
        - Munich (Box 136)
        - New York (Box 136)
          - Frick Collection (Box 136)
          - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 136)
        - Paris (Box 136)
          - Louvre (Box 136–137)
            - Bathsheba (Box 137)
            - Christ and the Disciples at Emmaus (Box 137)
            - Flayed Ox (Box 137)
        - Rotterdam (Box 137)
        - Stockholm (Box 137)
        - Stuttgart (Box 137)
        - Vienna (Box 137)
        - Washington (Box 137)
          - Apostle Paul (Box 137)
          - Circumcision (Box 138)
          - Lady with an Ostrich Feather (Box 138)
          - Joseph Accused by Potiphar's Wife (Box 138)
          - The Mill (Box 138)
          - Polish Nobleman (Box 138)
          - Self-Portrait (Box 138)
    - RUYSDAEL, Jacob Salomonsz van, ca. 1629-1681 (Box 138)
      - Amsterdam (Box 138)
      - Chicago (Box 138)
      - Dresden (Box 138)
      - London (Box 138)
      - New York (Box 138)
      - Paris (Box 138)
      - Rotterdam (Box 138)
      - Washington (Box 138)
    - RUYSDAEL, Salomon van, ca. 1602-1670 (Box 138)
    - SAENREDAM, Pieter Jansz, 1597-1665 (Box 138)
    - SCOREL, Jan van, 1495-1562 (Box 138)
    - SEGHERS, Hercules, 1590-ca. 1640 (Box 138–139)
    - STEEN, Jan, ca. 1626-1679 (Box 139)
      - Amsterdam (Box 139)
      - Berlin (Box 139)
      - Chicago (Box 139)
      - Hague (Box 139)
      - London (Box 139)
      - Washington (Box 139)
    - SWEERTS, Michael, 1618-1664 (Box 139)
    - TERBORCH, Gerard II, 1617-1681 (Box 139)
      - Berlin (Box 139)
      - Dresden (Box 139)
      - Hague (Box 139)
      - Leningrad (Box 139)
      - London (Box 139)
      - New York (Box 139–140)
    - TER BRUGGHEN, Hendrick, 1588-ca. 1629 (Box 140)
    - TOOROP, Jan, 1858-1928 (Box 140)
    - THORN-PRIKKER, Jan, 1868-1932 (Box 140)
    - TROOST, Cornelis, 1697-1750 (Box 140)
    - VAN GOGH, Vincent, 1853-1890 (Box 140)
      - Drawings (Box 140)
      - Paintings (Box 140)
        - Amsterdam or Laren (Box 140–141)
        - Boston (Box 141)
        - Chicago (Box 141)
        - Frankfurt (Box 141)
        - London (Box 141)
        - Moscow (Box 141)
        - New Haven (Box 141)
        - New York (Box 141)
        - Otterlo (Honderlo) (Box 141)
        - Paris (Box 141)
        - Upperville, VA (Box 142)
    - VELDE, Adriaen van de, ca. 1636-1672 (Box 142)
    - VELDE, Esaias van de, 1591-1630 (Box 142)
    - VELDE, Jan van de, II, ca. 1593-1641 (Box 142)
    - VELDE, Willem van de, II, 1633-1707 (Box 142)
    - VERKOLJE, Jan, I, 1650-1693 (Box 142)
    - VERMEER, Jan, 1632-1675 (Box 142)
      - Amsterdam (Box 142)
      - Berlin (Box 142)
      - Boston (Box 142)
      - Dresden (Box 142)
      - Frankfurt (Box 142)
      - Hague (Box 142)
        - Young Girl (Box 142)
        - View of Delft (Box 142)
      - New York (Box 142)
        - Bache Collection (Box 142)
        - Frick Collection (Box 142)
        - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 142)
      - Paris (Box 142)
      - Vienna (Box 142–143)
      - Washington (Box 143)
        - Girl with Flute (Box 143)
        - Girl with Red Hat (Box 143)
        - Woman Weighing Gold (Box 143)
    - VERSPRONCK, Joh (Box 143)
    - VICTORS, Jan, 1619-after 1676 (Box 143)
    - VINCKENBOONS, David, 1578-1629 (Box 143)
    - VRIES, Hans Vredeman de, 1527-after 1604 (Box 143)
    - WEENIX, V.B., 17th century (Box 143)
    - WERFF, Adriaen van der (Box 143)
    - WILLINK, Albert Carel, 1900- (Box 143)
    - WISSING, Willem, ca. 1656-1687 (Box 143)
    - WITTE, Emanuel de (Box 143)
    - WITTEL, Gasper van, 1653-1736 (Box 143)
    - WOUVERMAN, Joachim, 1566-1638 (Box 143)
    - WTTEWAEL, Joachim, 1566-1638 (Box 143)
- Painting Hungary (Box 143)
  - LAZLO, Peri, 1889- (Box 143)
  - MOHOLY-NAGY, Laszlo, 1895-1946 (Box 143)
- For PAINTING ITALY, see boxes 210-314 (pages 105-154) (Box 143)
- Painting Japan (Box 143)
  - FUJITA, Tsuguharu, 1886-1968 (Box 143)
- Painting Norway (Box 143)
  - MUNCH, Edvard, 1863-1944 (Box 143–144)
    - Bergen (Box 144)
    - Oslo (Box 144)
- Painting Poland (Box 144)
  - HALICKA, Alicia, 1895-1975 (Box 144)
  - KISLING, Moise (Box 144)
  - MARCOUSIS, Louis, 1882-1941 (Box 144)
  - ZAK, Eugenjusz (Box 144)
- Painting Portugal (Box 144)
  - GONCALVES, Nuno, fl. 1450-1471 (Box 144)
  - SOUSA-GARDOZO, 1887-1918 (Box 144)
- Painting Russia (Box 144)
  - 14th Century (Box 144)
  - 15th Century (Box 144)
  - 16th Century (Box 144–145)
  - 17th Century (Box 145)
  - 18th Century (Box 145)
    - ALTMAN, Nathan (Box 145)
    - ARCHIPENKO, Alexander (Box 145)
    - BAKSHEEVE, Vasili (Box 145)
    - BERMAN, Eugene, 1899- (Box 145)
    - BURLUK, David, 1882- (Box 145)
    - CHAGALL, Marc, 1887-1985 (Box 145)
      - Drawings (Box 145)
      - Paintings (Box 145–146)
    - CHRUZKIJ, Ivan, 1806-1855 (Box 146)
    - DENISSON, Alex (Box 146)
    - DIENEKA, Alex (Box 146)
    - DOBUZHINSKI, Mstislaw, 1875- (Box 146)
    - GE, N.N. (Box 146)
    - GERASIMON, A. (Box 146)
    - GONCHAROVA, Natalie, 1881- (Box 146)
    - GRABAR, Igor, 1871- (Box 146)
    - IVANOV, Alexsandr, 1806-1858 (Box 146)
    - KAKABADZE, David, 1890- (Box 146)
    - KANDINSKY, Vassily, 1866-1944 (Box 146)
      - 1880-1908 (Box 146)
      - 1909 (Box 146)
      - 1910 (Box 146)
      - 1911 (Box 146)
      - 1912-1913 (Box 146–147)
      - 1914-1925 (Box 147)
      - 1926-1944 (Box 147)
    - KARPOV, C. (Box 147)
    - KONCHALOVSKY, P.P., 1876-1956 (Box 147)
    - KOROTKOVA, Nina (Box 147)
    - KRAMSKOI, Ivan (Box 147)
    - KUKRYNSKI (Box 147)
    - LEBEDEV, K.V. (Box 147)
    - LEVITAN, J.J. (Box 147)
    - LEVITSKY, D.C., 1735-1822 (Box 147)
    - LISSITZKY, El, 1890-1941 (Box 147)
    - MALEVICH, Kasimir, 1878-1935 (Box 147)
    - MERKULOV, A.A. (Box 147)
    - MODOROV, J.A. (Box 147)
    - MORAVOV, A.V (Box 147)
    - MORGUNOV, A. (Box 147)
    - NESTEROFF, Michail Vassilvitch, 1862- (Box 147)
    - PEROV, Vasily, 1834-1882 (Box 148)
    - PEVSNER, Antoine, 1886-1962 (Box 148)
    - PIMENOV, Iuri Iwanowitsch, 1903- (Box 148)
    - POLENOW, B.D. (Box 148)
    - POPOVA, Lyubov', 1889-1924 (Box 148)
    - PUNI, Ivan (Box 148)
    - REPIN, Ila Jefimovich, 1844-1930 (Box 148)
    - RODCHENKO, Alexander, 1891-1956 (Box 148)
    - ROKOTOV, Fedda, 1730-1808 (Box 148)
    - RUBLEV, Andrej (Box 148)
    - STELLETSKI, D.D., fl, 1903 ff. (Box 148)
    - SURIKOV (Box 148)
    - TCHELITCHEW, Pave., 1898-1957 (Box 148)
    - TOIDZE, I.M. (Box 148)
    - UDALZOWA (Box 148)
    - VASILIEV, V.A. (Box 148)
    - VASNETSOV, V.M., 1848-1927 (Box 148)
    - VENETSIANOV, Aleksey, 1780-1847 (Box 148)
    - WRUBEL, Michael, 1856-1910 (Box 148)
    - YEFANOV, V.P. (Box 148)
    - ZVEREV, Antatoly (Box 148)
- Painting United States (Box 148)
  - Southwest (Box 148)
  - Unknown Artists (Box 148)
    - 17th century (Box 148)
    - 18th century (Box 149)
    - 19th century (Box 149–150)
    - 20th century (Box 150)
      - COLLECTOR'S Homes (Box 150)
      - EXHIBITIONS (Box 150)
        - ARMORY Show (Box 150)
        - "291" (Box 150)
  - Known Artists (Box 150)
    - ABBEY, Edwin Austin, 1852-1911 (Box 150)
      - Drawing (Box 150)
      - Painting (Box 150)
    - ADAMS, Weyman (Box 150)
    - ALBERS, Josef, 1888-1976 (Box 150–151)
    - ALBRIGHT, Ivan Le Lorraine, 1897-1983 (Box 151)
    - ALEXANDER, Cosmo, 1724-1772 (Box 151)
    - ALEXANDER, Henry, 1860-1895 (Box 151)
    - ALEXANDER, John W., 1856- (Box 151)
      - Boston (Box 151)
      - New York (Box 151)
      - Pittsburgh (Box 151)
      - Washington (Box 151)
    - ALLSTON, Washington, 1779-1843 (Box 151)
      - Andover (Box 151)
      - Boston (Box 151)
      - Brooklyn (Box 151)
      - Cambridge (Box 151)
      - New Haven (Box 151)
      - New York (Box 151)
      - Petworth, Sussex (Box 151)
      - Philadelphia (Box 151)
      - Washington (Box 151)
    - ARNOLD, E. (Box 151)
    - ATHERTON, John (Box 151)
    - AUDOBON, John James, 1785-1851 (Box 152)
    - AUSTIN, Darrel (Box 152)
    - AVERY, Milton, 1893- (Box 152)
    - AVINOFF, Audrey, 1884- (Box 152)
    - BADGER, Joseph, 1708-1765 (Box 152)
    - BAKER, Anna (Box 152)
    - BARNES, Matthew, 1880- (Box 152)
    - BASING, Charles, 1865-1933 (Box 152)
    - BAZIOTES, William, 1911- (Box 152)
    - BEAL, Gifford, 1879- (Box 152)
    - BEARD, William, 1824-1900 (Box 152)
    - BEAUX, Cecelia, 1855-1942 (Box 152)
    - BECK, Dunbar, 1902- (Box 152)
    - BELLOWS, George, 1882-1925 (Box 152)
      - Drawing (Box 152)
      - Painting (Box 152)
        - Andover (Box 152)
        - Boston (Box 152)
        - Chicago (Box 152)
        - Cleveland (Box 153)
        - New Britain (Box 153)
        - New York (Box 153)
        - Washington (Box 153)
    - BENBRIDGE, Henry, 1744-1812 (Box 153)
    - BENSON, Frank, 1862- (Box 153)
    - BENTON, Thomas Hart, 1889-1975 (Box 153)
      - Brooklyn (Box 153)
      - New York (Box 153)
    - BIERSTADT, Albert, 1830-1902 (Box 153)
    - BILLINGS, Henry, 1901-1987 (Box 153)
    - BINGHAM, George Caleb, 1811-1879 (Box 153)
      - Columbia, MO (Box 153)
      - Kansas City (Box 153)
      - New York (Box 153)
      - St. Louis (Box 153)
    - BISHOP, Isabel, 1902-1988 (Box 153)
    - BLACKBURN, Joseph, fl. 1754-1763 (Box 153)
      - Amherst (Box 153)
      - Boston (Box 153)
      - Brooklyn (Box 153)
      - Brunswick (Box 153)
      - New York (Box 153)
      - Plymouth (Box 153)
    - BLAKELOCK, Ralph, 1847-1919 (Box 154)
    - BLANCHARD, Carol (Box 154)
    - BLASHFIELD, Edwin H., 1848-1936 (Box 154)
    - BLOCH, Albert (Box 154)
    - BLOOM, Hyman, 1913- (Box 154)
    - BLUEMMER, Oscar (Box 154)
    - BLUM, Robert, 1857-1903 (Box 154)
    - BLUME, Peter, 1906- (Box 154)
    - BLYTH, Benjamin, 1740-1781 (Box 154)
    - BLYTHE, David Gilmour, 1815-1865 (Box 154)
    - BOHROD, Aaron (Box 154)
    - BONNAT, William (Box 154)
    - BOUCHE, Louis, 1896- (Box 154)
    - BRACKMAN, Robert, 1896- (Box 154)
    - BRADFORD, Francis, 1898- (Box 154)
    - BREHAN, Marquise de, fl. 1786-1789 (Box 154)
    - BRIDGES, Charles, fl. 1730-1750 (Box 154)
    - BRINLEY, D. Putnam, 1879- (Box 154)
    - BROOK, Alexander (Box 154)
    - BROWN, George Loring, 1814-1889 (Box 154)
    - BROWN, John George, 1831-1913 (Box 154)
    - BROWN, Mather, 1761-1831 (Box 154–155)
    - BROWNE, George, 1871- (Box 155)
    - BRUCE, Edward (Box 155)
    - BRUCE, Patrick, 1880-1937 (Box 155)
    - BRUSH, George de Forest, 1855-1941 (Box 155)
    - BULLER, Audrey, 1902- (Box 155)
    - BUNCE, William, 1840-1916 (Box 155)
    - BUNKER, Dennis, 1861-1890 (Box 155)
    - BURCHFIELD, Charles (Box 155)
    - BURLIN, Paul, 1886- (Box 155)
    - BURROUGHS, Bryeon, 1869-1934 (Box 155)
    - BUTTERSWORTH, James F. (Box 155)
    - CADMUS, Paul, 1823-1889 (Box 155)
    - CAMPBELL, Alex, fl. 1775 (Box 155)
    - CANDELL, Victor (Box 155)
    - CANDELL, Victor (Box 155)
    - CARLSON, John F., 1875- (Box 155)
    - CARROLL, John F., 1892- (Box 155)
    - CASSATT, Mary, 1844-1926 (Box 155)
      - Andover (Box 155)
      - Chicago (Box 155)
      - Cleveland (Box 155)
      - New York (Box 155)
      - Washington (Box 155)
    - CASTELLON, Federico (Box 155)
    - CATLIN, George, 1796-1872 (Box 155)